<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article desc="filters support">
   <meta desc="This article presents the support for SVG filters specification" />
   The following filters are supported in the library
   <note>See <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/SVG11/filters.html">Filter Effects</a></note>:
   <ul>
      <li>
         <code>feFlood</code>: This filter primitive creates a rectangle filled with color and opacity values</li>
      <li>
         <code>feImage</code>: This filter primitive refers to a graphic external to this filter element</li>         
      <li>
         <code>feGaussianBlur</code>: This filter primitive performs a Gaussian blur on the input image</li>                  
      <li>
         <code>feDiffuseLighting</code>: This filter primitive lights an image using the alpha channel as a bump map.
         The resulting image depends on the light color, light position and surface geometry of the input bump map.</li>                           
      <li>
         <code>feSpecularLighting</code>: This filter primitive lights a source graphic using the alpha channel as a bump map. 
         The resulting image depends on the light color, light position and surface geometry of the input bump map</li>                                    
      <li>
         <code>feDropShadow</code>: This filter creates a drop shadow of the input image. Note
         that it is a filter specified in SVG 1.2<note>See <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/SVGFilter12/#feDropShadowElement">SVG Filters 1.2, Part 2</a></note>
      </li>                           
      <li>
         <code>feOffset</code>: This filter primitive offsets the input image relative to its current position in the image space by the specified vector.</li>                        
      <li>
         <code>feMerge</code>: This filter primitive composites input image layers on top of each other</li>                                 
      <li>
         <code>feComposite</code>: This filter performs the combination of the two input images pixel-wise in image space using one of the Porter-Duff compositing operations</li>                                          
   </ul>
   
   <title title="supported lights" />
   The following lights elements are supported under the <code>feDiffuseLighting</code> and <code>feSpecularLighting</code>
   elements:
   <ul>
      <li>
         <code>feDistantLight</code>
      </li>
      <li>
         <code>fePointLight</code>
      </li>      
      <li>
         <code>feSpotLight</code>
      </li>          
   </ul>
   
   <title title="limitations" />
   <ul>
      <li>For the moment, the light effects are not correctly handled in a some of the cases</li>
      <li>A lot of the Porter-Duff compositing operations used in the <code>feComposite</code> filter are not converted correctly to the
         JavaFX equivalent</li>
   </ul>
            
   <cat id="support" />
</article>
